当今世界有如此多的文字，但我们几乎没有人有足够的时间
There's so much text in today's world, pretty much none of us have enough time to read all
来阅读这些文字
the things we wish we had time to
因此，我认为，大语言模型最令人兴奋的应用之一
So one of the most exciting applications I've seen of large language models is to use it
是用它来对文本进行总结
to summarize text
这也是我看到多个团队在不同软件应用中构建的东西
And this is something that I'm seeing multiple teams build into multiple software applications
你可以在ChatGPT网站上这样做
You can do this in the ChatGPT web interface
我经常用这种方式来总结文章
I do this all the time to summarize articles so I can just kind of read the content of
这样我就可以比以前多读很多文章
many more articles than I previously could
你将在本课程中，学习如何以编程方式来实现这个任务
And if you want to do this more programmatically, you'll see how to in this lesson
因此，让我们深入研究代码，看看你如何使用它来总结文本
So that's let's dig into the code to see how you could use this yourself to summarize text
让我们从之前的初始代码开始，导入openai，加载
So let's start off with the same starter code as you saw before of import openai, load the
API Key，这里是get_completion辅助函数
API key and here's that get_completion helper function
我将以“总结此产品评价”的任务作为运行示例
I'm going to use as the running example, the task of summarizing this product review
我为女儿的生日买了这只熊猫毛绒玩具，女儿非常喜欢
Got this panda plush toy for my daughter's birthday
无论去哪儿都要带上它，诸如此类
and so on and so on
如果你正在建立一个电子商务网站，并且有大量的评论
If you're building an e commerce website, and there's just a large volume of reviews
有一个工具可以用来总结冗长的评论，给你提供一种方式
having a tool to summarize the lengthy reviews could give you a way to very quickly glance
让你可以浏览更多评论，更好地了解所有客户的想法
over more reviews to get a better sense of what all your customers are thinking
因此，这里有一个生成摘要的提示
So here's a prompt for generating a summary
你的任务是对电子商务网站上的产品评论生成一个简短的总结，总结如下
Your task is generate a short summary of a product review from e commerce website, summarize
下面的评论等等，最多只能用30个字
review below, and so on, in at most 30 words
因此，这个柔软可爱的熊猫毛绒玩具受到女儿的喜爱，但价格有点小贵
And so this is soft and cute panda plush toy loved by daughter, but small for the price
提前到货
arrived early
还不错
Not bad
这是个相当好的总结
It's a pretty good summary
正如你在前面的视频中看到的，你还可以玩一些东西，比如控制
And as you saw in the previous video, you can also play with things like controlling
字符数或句子数来影响这个摘要的长度
the character count or the number of sentences to affect the length of this summary
现在，有时在创建一个摘要时，如果你有一个非常具体的目的
Now sometimes when creating a summary, if you have a very specific purpose in mind for
例如，你想给运输部门提供反馈
the summary, for example, if you want to give feedback to the shipping department, you can
你也可以修改提示来突出这点，这样他们就可以生成一个更好的总结
also modify the prompt to reflect that so that they can generate a summary that is more
适用于你业务中的一个特定群体
applicable to one particular group in your business
例如，如果我想要给运输部门反馈
So for example, if I add to give feedback to the shipping department, let's say I change
那么我会将关注点集中在商品的运输和交付等方面
this to start to focus on any aspects that mention shipping and delivery of the product
如果我运行这个指令，那么你会得到一个新的摘要
And if I run this, then again, you get a summary, but instead of starting off with soft and
这次不是以“柔软可爱的熊猫毛绒玩具”开始，而是强调它比预期提前了一天送达
cute panda plush toy, it now focuses on the fact that it arrived a day earlier than expected
然后它仍然有其他细节
And then it still has, you know, other details
或者作为另一个例子，如果我们不是想给运输部门提供反馈
Or as another example, if we aren't trying to give feedback to the shipping department
而是给定价部门提供反馈
but let's say we want to give feedback to the pricing department
定价部门负责确定产品的价格
So the pricing department is responsible for determining the price of the product
我会告诉它专注于与产品价格和感知价值相关的任何方面
And I'm going to tell it to focus on any aspects that are relevant to the price and perceived
价值
value
那么这将生成一个不同的总结，它说
Then this generates a different summary that it says
也许这个尺寸的价格可能太高了
maybe the price may be too high for a size
现在，在我为运输部门或定价部门生成的摘要中
Now in the summaries that I've generated for the shipping department or the pricing department
它更侧重于与这些特定部门有关的信息
it focuses a bit more on information relevant to those specific departments
事实上，你可以随时暂停视频
And in fact, feel free to pause the video now and maybe ask it to generate information
然后让它为负责产品客户体验的部门提供有关产品的信息
for the product department responsible for the customer experience of the product or
或者为你认为对电子商务站点有趣的其他某些方面提供信息
for something else that you think might be interesting to an e-commerce site
但在这些摘要中，尽管它生成了与运输有关的信息
But in these summaries, even though it generated the information relevant to shipping, it had
但也有一些其他信息，你可以决定这些信息是否有帮助
some other information too, which you could decide may or may not be helpful
因此，根据你想要总结的方式，你也可以要求它提取信息
So depending on how you want to summarize it, you can also ask it to extract information
而不是对其进行总结
rather than summarize it
因此，这里有一个提示，说你的任务是
So here's a prompt that says you're tasked to extract relevant information to give feedback
提取相关的信息来反馈给给运输部门
to the shipping department
现在它只是说，产品比预期早到了一天，没有其他的信息
And now it just says, product arrived a day earlier than expected without all of the other
这在一般的总结中也是有帮助的，但如果想知道运输方面发生了什么
information, which was also helpful in a general summary, but less specific to the shipping
就不那么具体了
department if all it wants to know is what happened with the shipping
最后，让我与你分享一个具体的例子，说明如何在工作流程中使用这个方法
Lastly, let me just share with you a concrete example for how to use this in a workflow
来帮助总结多个评论，使其更容易阅读
to help summarize multiple reviews to make them easier to read
因此，这里有几条评论
So here are a few reviews
这有点长，但这是对落地灯的第二个评论
This is kind of long, but here's a second review for a standing lamp
需要一盏灯放在卧室里
need a lamp on a bedroom
这是关于电动牙刷的第三条评论
Here's a third review for an electric toothbrush
我的牙科保健师推荐的
My dental hygienist recommended
关于电动牙刷的评论有点长
Kind of a long review about the electric toothbrush
这是关于搅拌机的评论，当时它说是季节性销售的17件套装系统
This is a review for a blender when it said, so said 17 piece system on seasonal sale and
诸如此类
so on and so on
这实际上是很多的文字
This is actually a lot of text
如果你愿意，可以随意暂停视频，读完这些文字
If you want, feel free to pause the video and read through all this text
但是，如果你想知道这些评论者写了什么，而不必停下来阅读所有的
But what if you want to know what these reviewers wrote without having to stop and read all
这方面的细节呢？
this in detail?
所以我要把 review_1 设为我们之前展示的那个产品评论
So I'm going to set review_1 to be just the product review that we had up there
我将把所有这些评论放到一个列表中
I'm going to put all of these reviews into a list
现在，如果我对这些评论实施一个for循环
And now if I implement a for loop over the reviews
这是我的提示，我要求它最多用20个字来总结它
So here's my prompt and here I've asked it to summarize it in at most 20 words
然后让它得到响应并打印出来
Then let's have it get the response and print it out
让我们运行这个程序
And let's run that
它打印出的第一条评论是熊猫玩具的评论，灯的总结评论
And it prints out the first review is that PandaToy review, summary review of the lamp
牙刷的摘要评论，然后是搅拌器
summary review of the toothbrush, and then the blender
因此，如果你有一个网站，你有数百条评论，你可以想象你如何
And so if you have a website where you have hundreds of reviews, you can imagine how you
使用它来建立一个控制面板，为大量的评论，生成简短的摘要
might use this to build a dashboard, to take huge numbers of reviews, generate short summaries
这样你或其他人就可以更快地浏览这些评论
of them so that you or someone else can browse the reviews much more quickly
然后，如果他们愿意，可以点击查看原始的长篇评论
And then if they wish, maybe click in to see the original longer review
这可以帮助你更高效地了解所有客户的想法
And this can help you efficiently get a better sense of what all of your customers are thinking
好了，总结就到这里
All right, so that's it for summarizing
我希望你能想象一下，如果你有任何有许多文本的应用
And I hope that you can picture if you have any applications with many pieces of text
你可以使用这样的提示来总结，帮助人们快速了解文字中的内容和各种文本
how you can use prompts like these to summarize them to help people quickly get a sense of
可以选择进一步深入挖掘
what's in the text, the many pieces of text, and perhaps optionally dig in more
如果有需要的话
if they wish
在下一个视频中，我们将看到大语言模型的另一个能力，即
In the next video, we'll look at another capability of large language models, which is to make
推断的能力
inferences using text
例如，如果你有一些产品评论数据
For example, what if you had, again, product reviews, and you wanted to very quickly get
你希望快速了解哪些评论具有积极或消极情感，该怎么办？
a sense of which product reviews have a positive or a negative sentiment?
让我们在下一个视频中看看如何实现这个功能
Let's take a look at how to do that in the next video